A Guide to the Additional Papers Of Alan Cheuse, 1991-1992
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Additional Papers Of Alan Cheuse 1991-1992
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10726-j
This collection consists of ca. 515 items (3 Hollinger boxes, ca. 1 linear shelf foot).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Users must obtain the permission of Alan Cheuse for access to the collection.
Acquisition Information
Alan Cheuse of Fairfax, Virginia, placed his papers on loan to the Library on June 24, 1992.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to the papers of Alan Cheuse, George Mason University, Fairfax, Virginia, contains ca. 515 items (3 Hollinger boxes, ca. 1 linear shelf foot), 1991-1992, and consists of personal, literary, and professional correspondence, typescripts of book reviews by and about him, a typescript of a short story "The Plan" by Alan Cheuse, an appointment book, printed material, articles such as "The Situation of Reviewing" and the review of the year in literature for The Encyclopedia Britannica(1991), his forward to The Kidnapped Saint by B. Traven, a cassette tape recording of a review of Robert Stone's novel, Outerbridge Reach, and an interview with Robert Stone, and miscellaneous articles and short stories not by Alan Cheuse, including Richard Elman, Ron Carlson, and Edward Hirsch.
Correspondents include:
John W. Aldridge (1991 Oct 24, Dec 19; 1992 Mar 22); Rick Bass (1991 Sep 7, 22, and 27, Oct 16, Dec 3, 20 and 24; 1992 Jan 6, Feb 3 and 25, Mar 30); Richard Bausch (1991 Jun 24; n.d.); Charlie Baxter (1991 Aug 21, Nov 24; 1992 Mar 29); Ann Beattie (1991 Jul 12, Aug 9, Oct 3); Steve Becker (1991 May 29, Oct 24; 1992 Jan 3, Mar 5); Madison Smartt Bell (Aug 25, Dec 9); Pinckney Benedict (1991 Nov 23; 1992 Jan 23); Dulcy Brainard (1991 May 26); Ron Carlson (1991 Sep 2); Jonathan Carroll (1992 Feb 19); Michelle Carter (1991 Jul 20); Fred Chappell (1992 Mar 22); Amy Willard Cross,(1991 Sep 20); Lee Cullum (1991 Sep 18, Oct 28; 1992 Jan 7 and 15); Richard Currey (1991 Sep 24); Nicholas Delbanco (1991 May 16); Rick Demarinis (1992 Jan 3); Robb Forman Dew (1992 Feb 28); Annie Dillard (1991 Sep 25); E.L. Doctorow. (1991 Sep 17); Carolyn Doty (1991 Oct 7; 1992 Mar 6); Stu Dybek (1991 Jul 28; n.d.); Richard Elman (1991 Jul 26, Dec 17; 1992 Apr 13); Richard Ford,(1991 Jun 21); Laura Furman (1991 Sep 19); George Garrett (1992 Feb 4, 5, and 7); Dagoberto Gilb (1991 Aug 21, Oct 19, Nov 4 and 19; 1992 Feb 7); Herbert Gold (1992 Mar 15); Doris Grumbach (1991 Sep 14); Albert Haley (1991 Nov 20); Oakley Hall (1991 Sep 17, Oct 30); Sam Halpert (1991 Apr 23); Patricia Hampl (1991 Aug 19); Ron Hansen (1991 Oct 23, Nov 13); Jim and Jeanne Houston, (1991 Oct 31, Dec 15); Josephine Humphreys (1992 Apr 5); David Kaplan (1991 Jun 10, Aug 26, Sep 16); Patricia Lear, (1991 Jul 11); Don [Lee ?] (1991 May 23, Dec 3); Jim Lehrer (1991 Sep 18); Barry Lopez (1991 Aug 20); James McManus (1991 Nov 10); David Madden (1991 Jul 14; 1992 Jan 23); Clarence Major, (1991 Jun 27); Ann Malamud (1991 Oct 26; 1992 Feb 28, Mar 9); Mary Morris (1991 Jul 7 and 22); Faye Moskowitz (1991 Oct 8, Nov 30); Carl Navarre (1991 Sep 10; 1992 Jan 27); Deborah Navas, (1991 Aug 14); Howard Norman (1991 Aug 20; 1992 Mar 3; n.d.); Debra Nystrom (1991 Jul 12, Oct 14); Dan O'Brien (1991 Aug 17); Camille Paglia (1991 Aug 31); Daniel Peters (1992 Mar 7); Robert [Pinsky?] (1992 Mar 1); Roxana Robinson (1991 Jul 25); Scott Sanders (1991 Nov 22); Lore Segal,(1991 Dec 19); Neila Seshachari (1991 Nov 27); Robbie Shapard (1991 Jul 11, Nov 8; 1992 Feb 21); Anna Shapiro (n.d.); Barry Silesky (1991 Oct 14 and 24; 1992 Feb 22); Lee Smith (1991 Jul 6; [1992]); Wallace and Marion Stegner, (Sep 6 and Nov 26; 1992 Feb 20); Daniel Stern (Nov 22, Dec 9); Nan A. Talese (1991 Jul 15); John Updike (1991 Jul 2); Robert Ward (1991 Sep 22); Allen Wier (1991 Jul 12 and 28); Jon Manchip White (1991 Apr 25, Aug 18, Sep 11, Oct 30; 1992 Apr 5); C.K. Williams (1991 Jun 7, Aug 14, Sep 17, Nov 22; 1992 Apr 29); Jonathan Yardley (1991 Jun 17); Al Young (1991 Nov 3)
Subjects include: the decline of the Bennington Writing Workshop, (1991 Aug 18); "The Camel's Back" short story by Cheuse (1991 Aug 22); Melissa Gold obituary (1991 Nov 12) sent by Herbert Gold; The Grandmother's Club, a critique of a theatrical adaptation (1991 Jul 25); the death of Bernard Malamud (1991 Oct 26); "The Mexican Maid" short story by Alan Cheuse (1991 Aug 21, Dec 3; 1992 May 4)
Contents List
- Correspondence (8 folders) 1991 (Box 1)
- Correspondence (4 folders) 1992, n.d. (Box 2)
- Appointment Book belonging to Alan Cheuse 1991 (Box 2)
- "Forward" by Alan Cheuse to The Kidnapped Saint by B. Traven, with a letter from Shirley A. Cloyes re editorial changes 1991, 2 TMs (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous Articles and Short Stories, Etc. not by Alan Cheuse 1991-1992 (Box 2)
- "The Plan" by Alan Cheuse (Short Story) 1991, TMs (Box 2)
- Printed Material 1991-1992 (Box 2)
- Reviews by Alan Cheuse 1991-1992 (Box 3)
- Reviews of The Light Possessed by Alan Cheuse 1991 (Box 3)
- "The Situation of Reviewing" by Alan Cheuse, with a letter from Robert Shapard, April 19, 1991, re the Symposium 1991, TMs (Box 3)
- "The Situation of Reviewing" by Alan Cheuse, with a letter from Robert Shapard, June 12, 1991, re the Symposium 1991, galleys (Box 3)
- Smithsonian Seminar - Contemporary Southwestern Art and Literature, Santa Fe, New Mexico 1991 (Box 3)
- "The Year in Literature: 1991" in The Enclyclopedia Britannica by Alan Cheuse 1991, TMs (Box 3)
- "The Year in Literature: 1991" in The Enclyclopedia Britannica by Alana Cheuse 1991, Printed (Box 3)
- A review of Robert Stone's novel Outerbridge Reach(N.Y., Ticknor and Fields, 1992), and an interview with the author by Alan Cheuse [1992], CASSETTE TAPE (Box 3)
  (T-928)